export const GOVERNMENTA2010 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Government as a subject refers to the study of",
A: "territotrial expansion",
B: "political leaders",
C: "the various nations of the World",
D: "the institutions of the state",
answer: "D. the institutions of the state",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Government is distinguished from the state because it",
A: "can be changed periodically",
B: "does not operate in any defined territory",
C: "is a loosely organized structure",
D: "enforces its will on the people of the State",
answer: "A. can be changed periodically",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. A government is legitimate if it",
A: "comes to power through a coup d’etat",
B: "is not oppressive",
C: "provides social services for the people",
D: "has the mandate of the people to rule",
answer: "D. has the mandate of the people to rule",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. A sovereign power over a number of people in a specific geographical area is called",
A: "society",
B: "region",
C: "state",
D: "nation",
answer: "C. state",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Absence of government in a state is referred to as",
A: "anarchy",
B: "confusion",
C: "coup détat",
D: "ínstability",
answer: "A. anarchy",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. A situation where all the citizens meet in an open place to govern the state is called",
A: "direct democracy",
B: "electoral college",
C: "representative democracy",
D: "guided democracy",
answer: "A. direct democracy",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. A system of government in which the political power is vested in the elected representatives is known as",
A: "oligarchy",
B: "democracy",
C: "feudalism",
D: "Fascism",
answer: "B. democracy",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Sovereignty implies all the following except",
A: "the highest authority in a state",
B: "a state of political independence",
C: "unlimited powers of a state to make and enforce laws",
D: "the supremacy of political parties",
answer: "D. the supremacy of political parties",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Popular Sovereignty is located in the",
A: "military",
B: "police",
C: "electorate",
D: "opinion leaders",
answer: "C. electorate",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Popular Sovereignty is located in the",
A: "military",
B: "police",
C: "electorate",
D: "opinion leaders",
answer: "C. electorate",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. A system of government in which the leader exercises absolute power and allows no opposition is called",
A: "totalitariansim",
B: "capitalism",
C: "communism",
D: "socialism",
answer: "A. totalitariansim",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Which of the following is a basic component of political culture?",
A: "Cultural development",
B: "Cultural design",
C: "Cultural display",
D: "Cognitive orientation",
answer: "D. Cognitive orientation",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Communism, as propounded by Karl Max, was later interpreted by",
A: "Locke",
B: "Dicey",
C: "Bentham",
D: "Lennin",
answer: "D. Lennin",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. According to Karl Marx, those who own and control the means of production in a capitalist society are the",
A: "colonialists",
B: "workers",
C: "bourgeoisies",
D: "peasants",
answer: "C. bourgeoisies",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The Rule of law is limited by",
A: "free press",
B: "diplomatic immunity",
C: "constitutionalism",
D: "separation of powers",
answer: "A. Diplomatic immunity",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The institution created for checking abuses by a government department is known as the",
A: "secret service",
B: "judicial commission",
C: "ombudsman",
D: "corps marshall",
answer: "C. ombudsman",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. A good example of an absolute monarch is",
A: "Adolf Hitler of Germany",
B: "Benito Mussohni of Italy",
C: "Haile Salessie of Ethiopia",
D: "Margaret Thatcher of Britain",
answer: "C. Haile Salessie of Ethiopia",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The power of the central government to dissolve subordinate units at will is a feature of",
A: "confederal system of government",
B: "unitary system of government",
C: "parlimentary system of government",
D: "federal system of government",
answer: "B. unitary system of government",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Which of the following is a feature of federalism ?",
A: "Unwritten Constitution",
B: "Flexible Constitution",
C: "Unitary Constitution",
D: "Written Constitution",
answer: "D. Written Constitution",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The exclusive list in federalism includes all the following except",
A: "defence",
B: "foreign relation",
C: "currency",
D: "transportation",
answer: "D. transportation",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The order of mandamus is a",
A: "form of order by a superior body to perform a function",
B: "mandate from the executive to the public corporations",
C: "plea for man of alibi in court",
D: "writ to produce a detained person for trial",
answer: "A. form of order by a superior body to perform a function",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. In the legislature, a filibuster is one who",
A: "is in charge of party discipline",
B: "presents party manifesto during parliamentary system sessions",
C: "does not take part in law-making",
D: "prevents the passage of a bill by making long speeches",
answer: "D. prevents the passage of a bill by making long speeches",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Which of the following measures will ensure the independence of the judiciary? Judges",
A: "salaries must be handled by foreign banks",
B: "must be controlled by the president",
C: "salaries must be fixed and not subject to arbitary review",
D: "must not be separated from the executive",
answer: "C. salaries must be fixed and not subject to arbitary review",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The most important function of the Upper House in a federation is to",
A: "serve as the highest court of the land",
B: "ensure equal representation of the component units",
C: "provide a place for retired politicians in the legislature",
D: "invite politicians for questioning",
answer: "B. ensure equal representation of the component units",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The most important function of the Upper House in a federation is to",
A: "serve as the highest court of the land",
B: "ensure equal representation of the component units",
C: "provide a place for retired politicians in the legislature",
D: "invite politicians for questioning",
answer: "B. ensure equal representation of the component units",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Bi-cameral legislature is the same as",
A: "legislature with two chambers",
B: "one chamber legislature",
C: "the Upper House in any legislature",
D: "the Lower House in any Legislature",
answer: "A. unicameral legislature",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. A short break in parliamentary session is referred to as",
A: "suspension",
B: "recess",
C: "dissolution",
D: "termination",
answer: "B. recess",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The term guillotine in the legislature refers to",
A: "allocation of time to a bill",
B: "passing a bill into law",
C: "voting a bill into law",
D: "passing an appropriation bill",
answer: "A. allocation of time to a bill",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Th rights of individuals are usually enshrined in the",
A: "law books",
B: "courts",
C: "constitutions",
D: "journals",
answer: "C. constitutions",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. A citizen’s freedom of movement may be restrained if he",
A: "has refused to salute the Head of State",
B: "has been convicted by the courts",
C: "refuses to vote at elections",
D: "criticizes the government",
answer: "B. has been convicted by the courts",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. A major advantage of a one-party system is that it",
A: "prevents dictatorship",
B: "promotes unity",
C: "allows opposition",
D: "promotes freedom and liberty",
answer: "B. promotes unity",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Which of the following best describes the concept of enfranchisement Right",
A: "to campaign for candidates during elections",
B: "to sue and be sued",
C: "given to people to vote and be voted for",
D: "to free expression on political issues",
answer: "C. given to people to vote and be voted for",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The process by which voters may remove a public officer before the end of his term of office is called",
A: "referendum",
B: "gerrymandering",
C: "recall",
D: "bye-election",
answer: "C. recall",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The arrangement by which a country is divided into parts for election purposes is called",
A: "enfranchisement",
B: "gerrymandering",
C: "delimitation",
D: "democratization",
answer: "C. delimitation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. A yes or no vote cast by electorate to decide an important issue in an area is known as",
A: "franchise",
B: "plebiscite",
C: "electorate college",
D: "public opinion",
answer: "B. plebiscite",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The term winner-takes all can be associated with",
A: "second ballot system",
B: "representative government",
C: "first-past-the-post system",
D: "proportinal representation",
answer: "C. first-past-the-post system",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Anonymity of the civil servants means that they",
A: "are free from their political heads",
B: "are to be seen but not be heard",
C: "cannot vote for any political party",
D: "are to execute government policies",
answer: "B. are to be seen but not be heard",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The Loi-Cadre Reforms of 1956 in the French West Africa were as a result of",
A: "pressure from the French territories",
B: "change in French Policy of Association",
C: "opposition to Bamako Conference",
D: "British colonial policy of granting internal self-government",
answer: "A. pressure from the French territories",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Which of following best describes the status of Governor-General in British West African countries at independence? They",
A: "were representing the Queen of England",
B: "were above the law",
C: "maintained friendly relations with France",
D: "were the heads of government",
answer: "A. were representing the Queen of England",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Before the Second World War, the British Colonial Executive Council consisted of",
A: "only elected Africans",
B: "only White officials",
C: "unofficial members",
D: "official and unofficial members",
answer: "D. official and unofficial members",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. The West African Students’ Union worked towards",
A: "the end of colonial rule",
B: "the end of indirect rule",
C: "getting accommodation for West African Students",
D: "the end of the policy of direct rule",
answer: "A. the end of colonial rule",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The policy of Assimilation was abandoned because",
A: "it was too expensive to maintain",
B: "the French were fed up",
C: "the Africans liked it",
D: "it was less expensive",
answer: "A. it was too expensive to maintain",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The constitutional reforms in West Africa after the Second World War were geared towards",
A: "the assimilation of the people",
B: "the evaluation of colonialism",
C: "making the colonies independent states",
D: "making the people support their economic interests",
answer: "C. making the colonies independent states",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. One of the reasons for a military takeover in West Africa is",
A: "smooth administration",
B: "political stability",
C: "corruption among political leaders",
D: "good governance",
answer: "D. Togo",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Which of the following best describes the foreign policy of West African Countries during the Cold War?",
A: "Support for the Western bloc",
B: "Support for the Eastern bloc",
C: "Non-alignment with any power bloc",
D: "Allegiance to Nazi government",
answer: "C. Non-alignment with any power bloc",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Which of the following best describes the foreign policy of West African countries during the Cold War?",
A: "Support for the Western bloc",
B: "Support for the Eastern bloc",
C: "Non-alignment with any power bloc",
D: "Allegiance to Nazi government",
answer: "C. Non-alignment with any power bloc",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The Administrative Headquarters of the Economic Community of West African State (ECOWAS) is in",
A: "Freetown",
B: "Lome",
C: "Banjul",
D: "Abuja",
answer: "D. Abuja",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. A representative of one country in another within the Commonwealth of Nations is called",
A: "High Commissioner",
B: "Attache",
C: "Foreign Minister",
D: "Consul",
answer: "A. High Commissioner",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The use of veto power in the United Nations Organization (UNO) is only exercised by the",
A: "Economic and Social Council",
B: "International Court of Justice",
C: "Trusteeship Council",
D: "Security Council",
answer: "D. Security Council",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The head of the Commonwealth of Nations is the",
A: "Colonial Secretary",
B: "Australian Foreign Secretary",
C: "British Monarch",
D: "New Zealand Foreign Minister",
answer: "C. British Monarch",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]